Rudolf Höber Papers 1886-1961 Mss.Ms.Coll.44
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Publications and Miscellaneous, 1886-; 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1917; 2 items; Harms, Bernhard (Box 12)
    Newspaper articles on speeches by Prof. Berhard Harms from Blatt der Kieler Neuesten Nachrichten.
  - Leaving Germany: the account of Johannes U. Hoeber, 1938-1939; 15p.; Hoeber, Johannes U. (Box 12)
    Translated from German by Francis W. Hoeber, Oct. 17, 2003 from letters and diary entries.
  - Academic appointments, 1906-1921; 8 items; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Printed and typed documents regarding Höber's academic appointments.
  - "An meinen lieben Ullimuz, 1942 October 14; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Poem to his daughter.
  - Awards, certificates, etc., 1896-1952; Photocopies; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Copies of notification of successful examination for medical study at Erlangen (1894), approval of dissertation (1897), appointment to Kiel (1910) and promotion to Full Professor (1915), election to Leopoldinisch-Carolinische Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher (1922), Wiener Biologische Gesellschaft (1936); Virchow Society (1943), AAAS (1951), NYAS (1951), award from Deutsche Physiologische Gesellschaft (1951); award of Virchow Medal.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    Original retained by family.
  - "Begegnung", 1900-1901; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    2 copies each of "newsletters" Novemberheft 1900, Heft 4 (Jan. 1901); Heft 5 (Feb. 1901).
  - Biographical material, 1953-1957; Photocopy, 129p.; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Includes (inter alia): Amberson, William R., "Rudolf Höber: His Life and Scientific Work," Science 120 (1954):199-201; and Wilbrandt, W., "In Memoriam: Rudolf Höber," Experientia 9 (1953):1-3; and Wilbrandt, W., "Rudolf Höber," Ergebnisse der Physiologie, Biologischen Chemie und Experimentellen Pharmakologie 49 (1957); four typescript biographies; Höber genealogy.
  - "Das Lebendige als Objekt naturwissenschaftlicher Forschung", 1930; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Printed, Kiel, 1930.
  - "Membrane permeability to solutes in its relations to cellular physiology", 1936; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Reprint from Physiological Reviews 16 (1936): 52-102.
  - "Die Niederen Tiere", ca.1890s; Photocopy, 129p.; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Notebook on invertebrate zoology.
  - Photograph, ca.1950; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
  - Rektorats Jahr, 1930-1931; 1 folder; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Memoranda, correspondence, and notes regarding his position as Rektor at Unievrsity of Kiel.
  - "Über gemeinsam Erziehung", ca.1897-1910; 1 AMs; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Manuscript written while at Zurich.
  - "Ueber Experimentellen Shock durch Reizung der serüsen Häute", 1897; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873 (Box 12)
    Inaugural-Dissertation zur Erlangung der Medizischen Doctorwürde der Medizinischen Facultät zu Erlangen.
  - "Neue Versuche über die Aufnahme von Farbstoffen durch die rotten Blutkörperchen", 1931; 1 item; Höber, Rudolf, b. 1873; Pupilli, Giulio (Box 12)
    Pflügers Archiv für die gesamte Physiologie 226 (1931): 585-599.
  - "Record des Zuhürer 1024" (Academic sash), n.d.; 1 item (Box 12)
  - "Zur Erinnerung an den 9ten Mai" (Memorial volume of poetry), 1886 May 9; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d.; 5 items (Box 12)